# Gabriel Anderson

andgate.github.io

github.com/andgate linkedin.com/in/andgate in

## Objective

Highly skilled developer with 2 years of industry experience and 15 years of independent practice, seeking a frontend developer role where I can apply my ideation, relator, and strategic strengths, alongside my broad range of technical skills, to build awesome software that makes a difference in the world.

## Experience

## **SMART** Technologies

Seattle, WA

Frontend Software Developer

Aug. 2019 - Feb. 2021

- Designed and developed an Android overlay widget manager, written in Kotlin with an MVVM architecture.
- Decomposed a bloated widget framework into a set of packages as NPM monorepo using Lerna, to enable students to use the framework.
- Built a iOS-style calculator widget in React.
- Worked on a large frontend team for SMART Learning Suite Online.
- Did stuff on a large frontend team for company's main product, SMART Learning Suite Online.
- Projects were built to company standards, with Agile, Clean, and unit-tested modules.
- Attended daily team standups.
- Wrote technical design documentation on Confluence.
- Built and deployed projects using TeamCity, working closely with DevOps team to ensure projects were integrated into a large final product.
- Won company hackathon with teammates, developed interface in Vue and built a prototype zoom clone using WebRTC to assist senior developers.

## Central Washington University

Ellensburg, WA

Undergraduate Directed Research

Apr. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Under Dr. Arne Leitart, explored theories to develop more a efficient, parameterized approximation algorithm for the (Connected) r-Domination problem for unweighted and undirected graphs.
- New theories were explored on whiteboard and paper exclusively.

## Central Washington University

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

Teaching Assistant

Ellensburg, WA

- Graded homework assignments for Algorithm Analysis, taught by Dr. Boris Kovalerchuk.
- Graded homework assignments for *Introduction to Graph Algorithms*, taught by Dr. Arne Leitart.
- Assisted students during computer science lab hours for both classes.

#### Education

## Central Washington University

Ellensburg, WA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics Graduated Manga Cum Laude Sept. 2017 - Mar. 2019

3.7 GPA

## Projects

## Alonzo

github.com/andgate/alonzo

• Lambda calculus interpreter and repl written in Haskell.

#### solid-orbit

github.com/andgate/solid-orbit

• Published NPM package with solid-js hooks and components that provide an oribt-js data-layer.

[andelbulb Explorer github.com/andgate/mandelbulb]

Mandelbulb Explorer github.com/
• Raytracer with signed-distance field for mandelbulb written in C++ and glsl.

• SFML was used to provide interactivity.

## Skills

- Languages:
  - o Proficient: Javascript, Typescript, CSS, HTML, JSON, Java, Kotlin, C, C++, Haskell
  - o Familiar: C#, Swift, Python, GLSL
  - Frameworks: Node, React, Vue, Solid, kotlin-flow, OpenGL
  - Methodologies: Scrum, Clean, OOP, FP
  - Technologies: Android, Git, NPM, Webpack, Babel, Lerna, Docker, Bash, Emacs, VSCode, NixOS